see me draw a few pictures of your
看我画几张神经网络的图片
neural network in this video we'll talk
在这次课中我们将讨论
about exactly what those pictures means
这些图片的具体含义
in other words exactly what those little
换句话说就是我们画的这些
neural networks have been drawing on
神经网络的图片
represent and we'll starts with focusing
到底代表什么 我们首先关注
on the case of neural networks with
一个例子 本例中的神经网络
what's called a single hidden layer
只包含一个隐含层
here's a picture of a neural network let's
这是一张神经网络的图片
give different parts of these pictures
让我们给此图的不同部分
some names we have the input features x1
取一些名字 我们有输入特征x1
x2 x3 stacked vertically and this is
x2 x3 它们被竖直地堆叠起来
called the input layer of the neural
这叫做神经网络的输入层
network so maybe not surprisingly this
所以没什么好奇怪的
contains the inputs to the neural
它包含了神经网络的输入
network then there's another layer of
然后这里有另外一层
circles and this is called a hidden
我们称之为隐藏层
layer of the neural network I'll come
待会儿我会
back in a second to say what the word
回过头来讲解术语"隐藏"
hidden means but the final layer here is
的意义 但是这里最后一层
formed by in this case just one node and
在本例中 只由一个结点构成
this single note layer is called the
而这个只有一个结点的层
output layer and it's responsible for
被称为输出层 它负责
generating the predicted value y hat in
产生预测值y帽
a neural network the you train with
在一个神经网络中 当你使用
supervised learning the training set
监督学习训练它的时候 训练集
contains values of the inputs x as well
包含了输入x 也包含了
as the target outputs y so the term
目标输出y 所以术语
hidden layer refers to the fact that in
隐藏层的含义是 事实上
a training set the true values for these
在训练集中 这些中间结点的
nodes in the middle are not observed
准确值我们是看不到的
that is you don't see what they should be
也就是说你看不见它们
in the training set you see what the
在训练集中应具有的值 你能看见
inputs are you see what the output
输入的值 你也能看见输出的值
should be but the things in a hidden
但是隐藏层中的东西
layer are not seen in the training set
在训练集中你是无法看到的
so that kind of explains the name hidden
所以这也解释了词语隐藏层
layer just means you don't see it in a
只是表示你无法在
training set let's introduce a bit more
训练集中看到他们 现在我们再引入
notation where as previously we were
几个符号 就像之前
using the vector x to denote the input
我们用向量x表示输入特征
features an alternative notation for the
这里有个可代替的记号
values of the input features will be a
可以用来表示输入特征
superscript square bracket 0 and the
我们用a上标[0]来表示
term a also stands for activations and
而这个a也表示激活的意思
it refers to the values that different
它意味着网络中不同层
layers of the neural network are passing
的值会传递到它们
on to the subsequent layers so the input
后面的层中 所以输入层
layer passes on the value x to the
将x的值传递给
hidden layer so we're going to call that
隐藏层 所以我们将
call the activations of the input layer a
输入层的激活值称为a上标[0]
superscript 0 the next layer the hidden
下一层即隐藏层
layer will in turn generate some set of
也同样会产生一些激活值
activations which I'm going to write as
那么我将其记作
a superscript square bracket 1 so
a上标[1] 所以
in particular this first unit or this first node
具体地 这里的第一个单元或结点
we generate the value a superscript
我们将其表示为
square bracket 1 subscript 1 this second
a上标[1]下标1 第二个结点
node we generate the value now with a
的值我们记为
subscript 2 and so on
a上标[1]下标2 以此类推
and so a superscript square bracket 1
所以这里的a上标[1]
this is a four dimensional vector or if
是一个四维的向量
you write it in Python it gives us a four
如果写成Python代码 那么它是一个
by one matrix or four column vector
规模为4x1的矩阵或一个大小为4的列向量
which looks like this and it's four
就像我画的这样 它是四维的
dimensional because in this case we have
是因为在本例中 我们有
four nodes or four units or four hidden
四个结点 或者单元 或者称为四个
units in this hidden layer then finally
隐藏层单元 最后
the output layer will generate some
输出层将产生
value a two which is just a real number
某个数值a 它只是一个单独的实数
and so y hat is going to take on the
所以y帽的值将
value of a 2 so this is analogous to how
取为a上标[2] 所以这和
in logistic regression we have y hat
逻辑回归是相似的 我们有y帽
equals a and in logistic regression
直接等于a 在逻辑回归中
we only had that one output layer so we
我们只有一个输出层
didn't use the superscript square
所以我们没有用带方括号的上标
bracket but with a neural network we're
但是在神经网络中
now going to use this superscript square
我们将使用这种带上标的形式
bracket to explicitly indicate which
来明确地指出这些值
layer it came from one funny thing about
来自哪一层 有趣的是
notational conventions in neural networks
在约定俗成的符号传统中
is that this network that you're seeing
在这里你看到的这个例子
here is called a two layer neural
只能叫做一个两层的
network and the reason is that when we
神经网络 原因是当我们
count layers in neural networks we don't
计算网络的层数时 输入层
count the input layer so the hidden
不算进总的层数内 所以隐藏层
layer is layer 1 and the output layer is
是第一层 输出层
layer two another notational convention
是第二层 第二个惯例是
we're calling the input layer layer 0 so
我们将输入层称为第零层
technically maybe there are three layers
所以在技术上 这仍是一个三层的
in this neural network because this is
神经网络 因为
input layer the hidden layer and the
这里有输入层 隐藏层 还有
output layer but in conventional users if
输出层 但是在传统的符号使用者中
you read research papers and also in the
如果你阅读研究论文 或者
course you see people refer to this
在这门课中 你会看到人们将
particular neural network as a two layer
这个神经网络称为一个
neural network because we don't count input
两层的神经网络 因为我们不将
layer as a as an official layer
输入层看作一个标准的层
finally something that we'll get to
之后我们要看到的是
later is that the hidden layer and the
隐藏层以及
output layers will have parameters
最后的输出层
associated with it so the hidden layer
是带有参数的 这里的隐藏层
will have associated with their
将拥有两个参数
parameters w and b and I'm going to write
w和b 我将给它们加上
superscript square bracket 1 to indicate
上标[1] 表示这些参数
that these are parameters associated
是和第一层有关系的
with layer 1 with a hidden layer we'll
即和隐藏层有关系
see later that w will be a 4 by 3
之后我们会看到w是一个4x3
matrix and b will be a 4 by 1 vector in
的矩阵 而b是一个4x1的向量
this example where the first coordinate
在这个例子中 第一个数字4
4 comes from the fact that we have four
源自于我们有四个
nodes or four hidden units
结点或隐藏层单元
there and three comes from the fact that
然后数字3源自于
we have three input features we'll talk
这里有三个输入特征
later about the dimensions of these
我们之后会更加详细地讨论这些
matrices and it might make more sense at
矩阵的规模 到那时你可能
that time but in similarly the output
就更加清楚了 相似的
layer has associated with it also
输出层也有一些
parameters w superscript square bracket
与之关联的参数w上标[2]
2 and b superscript square bracket 2 and
以及b上标[2]
in terms of the dimensions of these are
从规模上来看 它们的规模
one by four and one by one and this one
分别是1x4以及1x1 这个1x4
by fours because the hidden layer has
是因为隐藏层
four hidden units the output layer has
有四个隐藏层单元而输出层
just one unit and we're going we'll go over
只有一个单元 之后我们会
the dimensions of these matrices and
对这些矩阵和向量的维度
vectors in a later video so you've just
做更加深入的解释
seen what a two layer neural network
所以你现在已经知道一个两层的神经网络
looks like that is a neural network with
什么样的了 它是一个只有一个隐藏层
one hidden layer in the next video let's
的神经网络 在下一个视频中
go deeper into exactly what this neural
我们将更深入地了解这个神经网络
network is computing that is how this
是如何进行计算的 也就是
neural network inputs x and goes all the
这个神经网络是怎么输入x
way to computing this output y hat
然后又是怎么得到y帽的